

PROFILE

Experienced biomedical Engineer with about 7 years of experience as an MRI/CT technician.

Final year PhD, working on Deep Learning for cardiac structure segmentation and analysis, with several publications and ongoing projects.

Excellent skills of problem resolving, team management, and driving overall operational improvements. Fast learner and strong team player.

CONTACT

+213 662 81 75 54 +213 794 25 67 35



alaa.amel@gmail.com a.laidi@univ-boumerdes.dz



in linkedin.com/in/amel-laidi-



researchgate.net/profile/Amel-Laidi-2

DIGITAL SKILLS

Matlab Python Machine/deep learning Image processing and analysis MS Office

LANGUAGES

Arabic: Native English: Excellent French: Advanced Turkish: Beginner

Amel LAIDI

PhD Student **Biomedical Instrumentation**

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCES

MRI / CT Technician, Medical Imaging Center "IHSSEN" [Apr 2016 – Present day]

MRI / CT Consultant, Canon Medical [August 2022- Present day]

Temporary Professor Mhamed Bougara University Boumerdes "Biomaterial technologies for prostheses" [Oct 2020 - Mars 2020]

Temporary Professor Mhamed Bougara University Boumerdes "Entrepreneurship and Project Management" [January 2023 - June 2023]

Temporary Professor Abd Hamid Ben Badis University Mostaganem "Introduction to Computer Science" [January 2023 - June 2023]

ACADEMIC TRAINING

PhD student, Biomedical Instrumentation [Since Jan 2019]

Master's degree, Biomedical Engineering: Medical Imaging AbouBekr Belkaid University Tlemcen

[Sep 2013 – Jun 2015]

Bachelor's degree, Biomedical Engineering: Signals and Images AbouBekr Belkaid University Tlemcen

[Sep 2010 – Jun 2013]

Global Understanding, Virtual Classroom AbouBekr Belkaid University Tlemcen & East Carolina University [Sep 2013- Dec 2013]

Deep Learning Specialization by Andrew Ng Coursera

[Jan 2020- Sep 2020]

"Al in Medical Imaging" **RISE-AFRICAI Winter School**

[Nov 2022]

GENERAL SKILLS

Adaptability
Team management
Fast learner
Team-spirited

HOBBIES

Reading Writing Content creation Traveling

PUBLICATIONS

Toward an automatic detection of cardiac structures in short and long axis views

January 2023 - Biomedical Signal Processing and Control

Deep Learning Models for Coronary Atherosclerosis Detection in Coronary CT Angiography

December 2022 - Current Medical Imaging Reviews

GAN Data Augmentation for Improved Automated Atherosclerosis Screening from Coronary CT Angiography

May 2022 - ICST Transactions on Scalable Information Systems

EXTRA CURRICULAR ACTIVITY

Lead of DSN Mostaganem Algeria

Data Scientists Network, an organization with a vision to build a world-class Artificial Intelligence (AI) knowledge, research and innovation ecosystem. committed to raising one million AI talents in 10 years.

Active member in "SisonkeBiotik"

SisonkeBiotik is an open and inclusive community of researchers, practitioners and enthusiasts at the intersection of Machine Learning and Healthcare working together to build capacity and drive forward grassroots research initiatives in Africa.

Volunteering mentor at the "Female Founders Mentorship Program" She Starts Africa – A community by women for women.

A social enterprise that aims to empower women and increase the number of women actively engaged in the economy.